I was not offended, but there are times
even pastors get offended.
I had a friend of mine in Baraton,
a pastor,
student.
And you know, Baraton, many students
struggle. Back then, I don't know if
things have changed. We have students
that even do a degree for 8 years.
You work,
you look for money, the day you get it,
you continue with a semester.
And this particular pastor noticed a
gap.
And started a grocery shop, a serious
one.
And would bring us even fruits
that we would only find in supermarkets.
And many people would support him
because he's a student, he has a wife,
he has two children, and he's also
looking for money to pay school fees.
I'm not so sure if he ever finished cuz
I've never seen him graduate. Those are
many years ago.
So, I got to buy in his shop.
And then,
another person comes
and he says, "Give me 1 2 3." And pastor
tells her, "Today I will not give you."
Then, he said,
You have a person when you go to the
clinic. When you have don't have money,
you come here.
And then, they began a small exchange,
you know? I'm listening. I'm listening.
I'm also listening as a student pastor.
And then,
this person says,
And I said, "So, pastors should open
shops for you.
You come and take things on credit.
You know, WE ARE TOO GRACIOUS. YOU
SHOULD NOT PAY. AND WHEN we ask you to
pay, we should be asking in loving
tones." Now, going to deliver it. You
know?
Pastor should be stepped on.
Heavenly Father, we glorify your name.
Indeed, it is wonderful to be in the
house of the Lord, and when we meet like
this,
we wouldn't want to move out or back to
our homes
because tarrying in your presence gives
us a sense of so much peace in our
hearts.
We want to thank you
that once again we have to have a moment
at your feet.
Even as you speak to us, challenging us
out of our comfort zones,
as we work for you
in readiness for your second coming.
Now, we pray you breathe life into the
message of today.
Let it shake the very foundations of sin
in our lives.
It is my prayer
that Lord, as you minister to us,
we in difficult circumstances, we don't
even know what to do.
We pray and plead with you
that your voice this day
will minister to our situations.
When we go back home,
we shall have so much peace in our
hearts.
Peace that surpasseth all understanding
to guard our hearts and to guard our
minds. Now, take captive of this meeting
as you dispel any forces of darkness
that could be present.
And even as you deal with agencies of
evil that would have come with a
different agenda, we bind their works
and schemes and plans in the mighty name
of Jesus.
Now, keep us until we finish is our
prayer in Jesus' name. Amen.
We have dinner. I have to keep repeating
that.
Be murders, drunkenness, revelries, and
he says the like to mean the least is
endless. He says will not inherit the
kingdom of God because they are in
righteousness alone dwells.
So we may succeed in distancing
ourselves
from the works of evil. You may not be
found in adultery. You may not be found
in fornication. You may not be found in
witchcraft or sorcery. You may not be
found in masturbation, solo sex. You may
not be found in pornography. You may not
be found in homosexuality. YOU MAY NOT
BE FOUND in drunkenness. You may succeed
in distancing yourself from all these
works of evil, BUT THERE ARE THREE MORE
other reasons that will PLACE ALL OF US
WHO ARE NOT PART of these three with
those who did evil to receive the same
condemnation like those who participate
in the works of evil.
So we said in the course of the week
that a prostitute may not see God, but a
child of God in his HOUSE MAY ALSO miss
heaven with an itch for not doing these
three things.
On Wednesday, is it on Thursday if I'm
not wrong?
One of them we said was failure to do
the work that would have fitted your
children
for a home
above.
The fact that you've not ready your
children
for the home above
will make you lose eternity.
You
and the robber
will be in the same place in hell.
There is no difference. Number two we
said, failure that was yesterday to use
the talent or talents God gave you to
serve him and serve humanity. Failure to
use them.
You will not see him when he comes.
Today
we look at one more reason
that can cost you eternity
if you did not associate yourself
with the works of evil.
The book is Matthew 25.
I will cruise through Matthew chapter 25
verse 31 to 33.
Let me begin from there.
Our Lord and God,
your word has no rival.
And no one goes wrong
when they decide to feed from your word.
Indeed it is a lamp unto our feet and
the light unto our path.
Herein lies the formula
to live in this world
in preparation for a world to come
that eye has not seen
nor ear has heard
nor mind has conceived.
As we cruise through your holy
scriptures,
once again we pray
imbue it with the power of the Holy
Spirit.
We are not here to speak down to people.
We are not here to condemn anyone.
But we are here to be moved closer to
you.
That our hearts may be inclined to
yourself.
That we may be able to keep your
judgments, your statutes, and your
This is our prayer in Jesus' name.
31 to 33.
I think I have some children here making
a lot of noise. If
their parents can handle them, I will be
glad.
When the Son of Man comes in His glory,
and all the holy angels with Him,
then He will sit on the throne of His
glory.
All the nations will be gathered before
Him,
and He will separate them one from
another,
as a shepherd divides his sheep from the
goats.
And He will set the sheep on His right
hand,
but the goats on the left.
A reminder of our title
is the sheep
on the right.
That when the nations are gathered
before the Lord,
there will be but two classes at the end
of the day.
And the eternal destiny
will be determined
by what they have done
or have neglected to do
for Christ
in the person of the poor,
in the person of the suffering.
Let me REPEAT THAT.
WE SAY THIS WORLD HAS AN END GOAL.
It is not as stable as you may think
that things continue as they were.
It is folding up
into something else.
And when He shall come,
we only have two classes of people,
the goat
or the sheep.
And our eternal destiny
is determined by what we have done or
what we have neglected to do for HIM IN
THE PERSON OF THE POOR and in the person
of the suffering.
And so Paul writes to the church in
Ephesus
in Ephesians chapter 2
verse 8 to 9
and is insisting
THAT WE ARE SAVED by grace through
faith. Listen carefully. And that not of
yourselves, it is the gift of God, not
of works, lest anyone should boast. To
mean what? To mean that salvation
is a gift from God that cannot be earned
by good works,
but is received by having faith in Jesus
Christ. Praise the Lord.
I love it because we always end it
today.
But there seems to be a sharp
contradiction
BY JAMES
WHO SAYS, "WE are justified BY WORKS."
WHILE PAUL is saying, "We are justified
BY WHAT? GRACE
THROUGH FAITH ALONE." James on the other
side seems TO CONTRADICT PAUL and says,
"We are justified by works and not by
faith only."
I will have to read that.
The book of James.
Permit me read that one.
James chapter 2.
Verse 14.
A little bit long or 10 verses, but
listen carefully. From verse 14, James
chapter 2.
What does it profit,
my brethren,
if someone says he has faith,
but does not have works?
Can faith save him?
If a brother or sister is naked
and destitute of daily food,
and one of you says to them,
"Depart in peace, be warmed and filled,"
but you do not give them the things
which are needed for the body, what does
it profit? I have had this experience
several times with our prayer ministry.
When we move into people's homes to pray
with them, and you see the great need
families have out here, and we pray with
them. We have always asked the Lord,
"Put money in our hands. We cannot be
praying for people, breaking down
demonic altars, and leave people
hungry."
And tell them, "The Lord will remember
you."
One time we visited a certain lady.
And this lady
is
working to go for studies in the US,
and has gotten everything ready,
saved money to apply for the visa.
And he says, "I only have 15,000." Was
it 15 or 16?
She said, "Commit me in prayer." And
tears are rolling down her eyes. Is a
mother of two
who's been abandoned by a husband.
Struggling alone. I salute women.
I salute women.
ABANDONED,
LEFT BY MEN
WHO MOVED TO CONTRACT OTHER MARRIAGES.
And you leave a woman with your own
flesh and blood TO STRUGGLE.
AND I'VE SEEN THEM STRUGGLE
and raise up people.
As she cries,
we prayed.
No way I'm seated. I'm saying,
could I give her the difference she's
looking for?
But I'm quiet.
And then we get to the car.
And when we all seated and have prayed,
we want to leave.
The one driving us,
my friend Sarah,
is Pastor, you know, I was seated there.
Feel like something is telling me, what
what is wrong if we give her the
balance?
And then the story continues behind.
Why can't we just collect this money
for this girl?
Enough of ministries where you pray for
people that they lack food and you leave
them without what? Food. AND YOU KNOW
TOO WELL YOU CAN GIVE THEM FOOD.
WHEN YOU SAY, "LORD, PROVIDE FOR THEM."
THE LORD WAS NOT GOING TO COME DOWN AND
GIVE THEM THE FOOD. THE LORD was going
to use you
to give the food.
No one else.
And so James is saying, "IF A BROTHER
SISTER is naked and destitute of daily
food
and one of you SAYS TO THEM, 'DEPART in
peace. BE WARMED AND FILLED. THE LORD is
with you. The Lord bless you. The Lord
never forgets his children. The Lord
will not forsake you. HE'S A PRESENT
HELP IN TIME OF TROUBLE.'
HE WILL FIGHT FOR YOU.
BUT YOU DO NOT GIVE THEM the things
which are needed for the body. What does
it profit?
THUS ALSO FAITH BY ITSELF,
IF IT DOES NOT HAVE WORKS, IS DEAD.
BUT SOMEONE will say, "You have faith
and I have works. Show me your faith
without your works and I will show YOU
MY FAITH BY MY WORKS."
YOU BELIEVE that there's one God. You do
well.
EVEN THE DEMONS BELIEVE. OKAY, TATA.
YOU THINK YOU'RE THE ONE WHO YOU'RE THE
ONLY ONE WHO BELIEVES THERE IS GOD. SO,
EVEN DEMONS KNOW
THAT THERE IS GOD. THESE VERSES WE KEEP
on quoting to people who ARE SUFFERING.
THE DEVIL knows how to quote them better
than us. IN FACT, DEMONS KNOW HOW TO
BEHAVE BEFORE THE LORD.
WHEN THEY HEAR THE NAME OF THE LORD,
THEY TREMBLE.
YOU, WHEN YOU HEAR THE NAME OF THE LORD,
you're on Facebook even right now as I
speak.
You're on Facebook.
You're busy booking a date
with your boyfriend.
When demons are trembling.
But do you want to know, OH FOOLISH MAN,
IS WHAT JAMES calls us. That faith
without works is what, church?
Is dead.
Was not Abraham our father justified by
works when he offered Isaac his son on
the altar?
Do you see that faith was working
together with his works and by works
faith was made perfect. And the
scripture was fulfilled which says,
"Abraham believed God, and it was
accounted to him for what, church? For
righteousness.
And he was called a friend of God." You
see then that a man is justified by
works and not by faith alone.
IS THE BIBLE CONTRADICTING ITSELF?
Because Paul has just said we are
justified by grace
through faith alone.
James is arguing we are justified by
works
and not only faith.
Is the Bible contradicting itself?
On the contrary, no.
Both Paul and James are right.
It's only a question of starting point.
Paul is discussing an individual WHO IS
JUST ABOUT to walk into the FAITH OF
JESUS. ANYONE
LIKE TODAY I'LL SAY, "HOW MANY WOULD
LIKE TO accept Jesus and move to the
waters OF BAPTISM?" THAT IS THE PERSON
PAUL IS DISCUSSING. BUT ON THE OTHER
HAND,
James is discussing an individual who
has long walked into the FAITH OF JESUS.
20 YEARS IN THIS CHURCH, 10 YEARS IN
THIS CHURCH, 5 YEARS IN THIS CHURCH.
THEY ARE READY FOR HIS COMING.
THESE two
these two thoughts
Paul's and James's
combined together
issues in a truth so undeniable,
a truth undisputed,
that we are saved by grace, yes, but we
shall be judged BY WORKS.
PRAISE THE LORD.
PRAISE THE LORD. WE ARE SAVED BY WHAT?
By grace. But we shall BE JUDGED BY
WHAT? BY WORKS.
We have heard enough Bible studies.
Every quarter there's a lesson
quarterly.
Every morning there's a sermon.
In the afternoon, there's Bible study.
It's enough.
We now need to move out and make our
Christianity practical. Because when he
comes, yes, you saved by grace, but our
judgement, whether you a sheep or goat,
is dependent on what you did or what you
neglected to do.
And so children of God, in that day,
Christ does not present before men the
great work he has done for them in
giving his life for their redemption.
That day, he presents the faithful WORK
THEY HAVE DONE FOR HIM, NOT WHAT HE HAS
DONE for them. WHAT YOU HAVE DONE FOR
HIM.
CALLED PRACTICAL CHRISTIANITY.
So verse 34 to 40.
Matthew 25.
Then the king will say to those on his
right hand,
"Come you blessed of my father, inherit
the kingdom prepared for you
from the foundation of the world.
For I was hungry and you gave me food.
I was thirsty and you gave me drink.
I was a stranger and you took me in.
I was naked and you clothed me.
I was sick and you visited me.
I was in prison and you came to me.
Then the righteous, I love that. They
are called the righteous. Then the
righteous will answer him saying, "Lord,
when did we see you hungry and feed you,
or thirsty and give you drink?
When did we see you a stranger and take
you in, or naked and clothe you? Or when
did we see you sick or in prison and
come to you? Verse 40, lovely. And the
king will answer and say to them,
"Assuredly, I say to you, inasmuch as
you did it to one of the least of these
my brethren, you did it to who?
To me."
Then he will say,
before I get to verse 41,
that marks another another bit.
I want you to take note.
Are you listening to me?
I want you to take note
that when you give food to the hungry,
when you give drink to the thirsty,
when you take in a stranger,
when you clothe the naked,
when you visit the sick,
when you go to the prisoner,
you are doing it
to Christ himself.
And you're doing it to Christ
in the person of this poor
and suffering
needy people.
So, this is my take.
If that be true,
that when I take in a stranger,
I am doing it to Christ in the person of
that stranger.
This is my take. Listen carefully. If
that be true,
then our service to that person, our
ministry to that person must be marked
with distinction.
It must be marked with excellence.
It must be marked with quality.
It must be marked with the BEST OF THE
BEST BECAUSE WE ARE DOING it for Christ
himself.
SO, WHEN WE DECIDE WE ARE GOING FOR A
CRUSADE,
WE DON'T COLLECT CLOTHES
THAT ARE TORN FROM OUR HOUSES.
I SAY, "WOMEN, bring all those clothes
you're not using so that we can use them
for THE CRUSADE." NO.
NOW, IT IS TIME WE MUST WALK INTO MR.
PRICE. It is time we must walk into
Woolworths. IT IS TIME WE WALKED INTO
We walked into
BOLO BESPOKE. IT IS TIME.
THAT IS WHERE YOU GO.
GET US AN OUTFIT.
WE ARE going to see Jesus.
Praise the Lord.
We are going to dress who?
Jesus.
You don't carry my change over here.
And then you say, "You know, this is
better than what they have."
Better than what you have? You can burn.
But because Christ is better than you,
then he must be given the best.
The best.
That challenges me.
But if I have to go home
and find a child
who is needy,
the way we go
to funerals, weddings, holidays, and
then you find a child in the village,
probably your relative, and you say,
And then you go to Nairobi
while you are going to go to the end.
When I end up bribing
and then you say
you know what you are saying. yeah.
When I wake up yeah. Surely I'm going to
get to the hotel.
Hey!
No way I need you.
I love you too and I could have gotten
you a car I do not want to say that you
are not my side I do not want to say
that you are not my side.
I didn't even say that you are not my
side.
I want to come to your kitchen Come let
us go to Nairobi too. You are not
thinking you are not my side. You are
not thinking you are not my side.
As you was a big not as you was a driven
four of them in different cars in your
home.
One goes to bright side. The other one
goes to Brookhurst. The other one is in
St. Christopher's.
Different direction every child with
their own car.
I want to go to your school and you go
to my condo.
I want to be happy and I want to be
happy
and I want to be happy.
And as your children come with big
English that cannot even be heard.
They can't be heard. They are twanging
MORE THAN A CAUCASIAN WOMAN. TWANGING
MORE THAN the owners of the language.
Who bewitched you?
I don't want to hear English I want to
twang with you not twang with you.
I want to be with you.
I want to be with you and I want to be
with you. I want to be with you and I
want to be with you.
I want to be with you. I want to be with
I want to be with you and I want to be
with you. I want to be with you. I want
to be with
I want to be with you and I want to be
with you. I want to be with you. I want
to be with you. I want to be with you. I
want to be with you.
I want to be with you and I want to be
with you. I want to be with you. I want
to be with you. I want to be with you. I
want to be with you. I want to be with
you.
I AM REPEATING.
WHEN YOU HELP THE YOU DID IT TO WHO?
To me. Because they will ask, "Where did
we see you so that we can feed you?" So,
if you helped anyone, it is me you did
it to.
When was the last time
you ministered to the poor
and the needy? I'm asking you.
When was the last time
This thing does not need you to be in
employment.
Hey,
going to Industrial Area Prison does not
need you to be earning 2 million.
Walking into Kenyatta Hospital does not
need employment.
You realize Christ is mentioning things
that people of every race walk in life
are able to do.
This is not just for the rich.
When was the last time you ministered to
the poor and the needy?
When was the last time you gave tangible
help, not just help, tang- help that can
be felt, help that can be touched,
tangible help? When was the last time
you did it
to the poor and the needy around you?
When was the last time?
Or for you,
all they desire or deserve are
leftovers, and then we deceive ourselves
that we have helped people.
When was the last time?
Do you know the feeling of picking
someone from Waruku here? You don't even
know them. Just picking them and tell
them, "Let's go to Quickmart down here."
Even if you don't want to go to town
CBD, let's go to Quickmart ingine hapa
chini. Let's go to Quickmart. Tell them
to to pick what they want.
You don't know them. Just tell them pick
what you want.
Pay.
Do you know the feeling?
Pick them from here, here, here.
I see them walk every evening as we go
from work.
Just pick them.
Pick them.
Let's go to Quickmart.
Today I met
a needy person
and I bought them breakfast.
Can we help people without robbing them
of their dignity?
When was the last time you helped a
needy person around you?
Christ shall ask you
when you dolled out the pittance of
bread to the starving poor.
When you go gave those flimsy garments
to shield them shield them from the
biting frost,
did you remember that you were giving it
to the Lord of glory?
Did you?
Did you remember
that this week you were giving you were
giving it
to the Lord
of glory.
This church is not just
a church from members that stay far away
from this place.
This church I've noticed have
people that come from Waruku here. True
or false?
Most of them are children, is it?
They are always here, determined,
committed every Sabbath,
mingling with our children.
And then our children will come from the
compound with the serious stories.
And as they tell the stories, they tell
them like they are owners of the money.
And this child sits at the corner there.
And for that day she will not mingle
because she has nothing to say, not
because she didn't want to go,
but because
the parent could not afford.
In fact, even if we paid for them today
that registration, I can assure you
there are still more things they would
need.
We are going for a compound. We need
heavy sweaters. We need sleeping bags.
Those children don't have.
Can you pick one child today
and say I'm sponsoring beyond 3,000 bob.
I am sponsoring this child. Let me know
what this child needs. I will take care
of it.
They're here with us.
And you will come here at the end of the
quarter in the church board. We have a
report from the children's ministries.
We went for camp out. 20 children.
Successful.
When there is no soul you touched,
reports are not for figures. Reports are
for soul winning.
How many souls did we win? How many
souls did we touch?
If you think you can support one child
for this camp out,
they just come from Maruku here, but
they're part of our children's ministry.
See the children's ministries direct.
Just see them.
The things we enjoy easily out here,
some people is far-fetched.
I thank God. Heaven will be an
equalizer.
Hey, hey, I thank God. I THANK GOD.
HEAVEN WILL BE WHAT? An equalizer.
There's no better for you
and a lesser one for me. SAYS IN MY
FATHER'S HOUSE, are many what? MANSIONS.
I GO TO PREPARE a place FOR YOU. THERE
IS NO MANSION DIFFERENT FROM YOU,
FIDELIS.
Heaven is an equalizer.
Road. We can all walk on the STREETS OF
GOLD.
>> FOR PRACTICAL CHRISTIANITY.
NOT ANYTHING ELSE. AND I PRAY
YOU WILL NOT AT ANY POINT THINK you want
to build a cathedral here.
This is enough. This is perfect.
It will remain like this a tent church
until Christ comes.
Even as we speak, it's already
comfortable but from the seats we want
to add for UNIFORMITY AND COMFORT.
BEYOND THAT, LET NO ONE COME to you with
A DREAM OF A CATHEDRAL HERE.
AND WE SPEND YEARS BEAUTIFYING OUR
SPACES,
MAKING THEM COMFORTABLE
when there is a work to be done.
This is enough.
Beautiful.
We don't need more than this. We only
need an extension.
And I pray the Lord gives you that land
where you've parked your vehicles. I
pray.
And for the Lord's cause, we will
capture it. We've already captured it
with our vehicles. This is wherever you
stop up on Joshua is yours.
It's 900 million money.
And I have said this repeatedly when I'm
preaching on this pulpit. This church a
few years you will not handle the
numbers.
This one here. I know what I'm talking
about. You will not handle the numbers.
You will not.
So, the development director,
church development
chair.
If there's anything you can do for us at
the moment,
is help us get wood.
That piece.
I am repeating.
And you will remember this speech.
In a few years, you will not handle the
numbers in this church.
The earlier you expand it,
the better.
There's a peace that is in this church.
I don't know whether I'm the one who
feels it every time I come.
There's a warmth when you walk into
Kilimani. A warmth of
of fellowship, of brotherliness.
When you get to the camera, I don't know
if you can come back
to me again. You get it?
But I don't know.
I don't know what I'm going to learn.
You get this very far. You get this in
Kamulu.
But you get this there's a person coming
from very far. You know very well me I
come from Kisumu. So, Kamulu here is not
a place
you tell us you cannot
come to to Kilimani. Very soon, you will
have people from all the slum regions
come here.
And they will need a means of transport.
I pray that time we shall have bought
buses
to transport people
to this place. I pray.
Because we are not opening branches.
This is the church.
And I'm making serious statements that
might find me in
in Githurai.
41 to 46 as I finish.
Then he will also say to those on the
left hand,
"Depart from me,
you cast into the everlasting fire.
You cast."
Hey, let me read it well.
Then he will also say to those on the
left hand,
"Depart from me, you cast
into the everlasting fire prepared for
the devil
and his angels.
For I was hungry
and you gave me no food.
I was thirsty
and you gave me no drink.
I was a stranger
and you did not take me in. Naked and
you did not clothe me. Sick
and in prison
and you did not visit me."
Then they will also answer him saying,
"Lord,
when did we see you hungry or thirsty or
a stranger or naked or sick or in
prison, and did not minister to you.
I have a problem with this kind of
people.
People that would want to treat you well
because they know you.
Hey, are you listening to me?
People that would want to pretend
they're angels, good, righteous,
because they know you.
There are places I've gone.
People have made noise, and then when
they realize it's Pastor Mokoro, the
tone changes.
Because now it is Mokoro.
But that is not who they are.
Treat me well even when you don't
know me.
Even when you don't know me.
I was on
a fleet of cars to a wedding.
You see, me I came to pray for the
couple.
And then we proceeded to church.
So me I arrived late
because I'm not part of the bridal
party.
Me I just came to pray.
In fact, I'm not even in the color
scheme of the wedding.
And so my car was not decorated.
You know, those cars are decorated so
that you identify who is who.
So we joined the
the fleet of vehicles to the venue.
And there were many vehicles.
So we had to maintain one lane
so that we don't disorganize
the other vehicles.
So I'm sandwiched between two vehicles
that are decorated.
But mine is not decorated.
And then one of them comes from behind.
I don't know from where he came from.
And came
and stopped just up in your my hand.
To me now I was not part of the
because there's no way to identify me.
Then when I rolled down the wind
he saw me and said, "Pastor, I'm sorry."
It was a very harsh tone.
But now the tone changed to a pastor.
Must you treat me well
because you know me?
Must you?
I was not offended. But there are times
even pastors get offended.
I had a friend of mine in Baraton.
A pastor
student.
And you know Baraton many students
struggle. Back then I don't know if
things have changed. We have students
that even do a degree for 8 years.
You work.
You look for money. The day you get it
you continue with the semester.
And this particular pastor noticed a gap
and
started a grocery shop, a serious one.
And would bring us even fruits
that we would only find in supermarkets.
And many people would support him
because he's a student. He has a wife.
He has two children. And he's also
looking for money to pay school fees.
I'm not so sure if he ever finished
because I've never seen him graduate.
Those were many years ago.
So I got to buy in his shop.
And then
another person comes
and he says, "Give me 1 2 3." And pastor
tells her, "Today I will not give
Then he said when you want to take money
pay
I need young sign in two months pay
I would like to pay
Then I want to take
I will go pay again
Now you take good care of her When you
have money you go again When you have
don't have money you come here
And then they began a small exchange you
know I'm listening I'm listening also
listening as a student pastor
And then
This person says You know I'm going to
buy a lot of pasta again again again
I said so pastor should open shops for
you
You come and take things on credit
You know WE ARE TOO GRACIOUS YOU SHOULD
NOT PAY AND WHEN WE ASK you to pay we
should be asking in loving tones number
only fit you know
Pastor should be stepped on
Who knows as you approach a rock
As you approach there are about three
four sharp corners
I know I'm going to kill a man I'm going
to kill you what a rock
As you approach a rock town from from uh
uh
I will kill you see you at the kitchen
town go to my way uh I will go to my way
I will go to my way I will go to my way
I will go to my way I will go to my
As you approach
a rock town just after the bush
uh
This is a new approach the town they are
about three very sharp bends
about three or four
So I am driving slowly because there are
trucks coming from the other side
So we are trying to help each other
negotiate the corners So, I have slowed
down Fidelis from 140. I have
slowed down
to be able to negotiate the corner with
two trucks that are coming.
So, when I slow down,
there's a vehicle behind me. I can look
at it from you mirror in a corner
windscreen
I can see.
Very impatient. Wants to overtake.
We are negotiating corners.
And then he started hooting at me. I
said, "What does this man want?" He
wants me to to move out of the road so
that he can pass. He looks to He seems
to be in a hurry. He hooted again.
So, I said, "Okay, good. Let me roll
down the the window huh? And ask him to
jump." See, this is what we do.
Clearly clearly there is nowhere to go
to There is nowhere can move to. We just
have to be patient with each other so
that so that we all get into Keroka
town.
And then the trailers passed and then he
overtook me, rolled down the windows,
gave me this look of
Then he say,
I said, "This this This title we have
will cost us because people supposed to
step on us and we should be very
gracious."
Then he slowed down completely, put
hazard, and was now driving in front of
me slowly very slowly. I also got
disgusted and I'm wondering what is his
intention. And then when we got to
Shell, there's this junction going to
Masimba. Huh?
So, he went and stopped right there. And
I also I also drove in front of him and
stopped.
And then he said, "Pastor Kanyai."
We need to be patient on these roads.
With people.
TREAT ME WELL, NOT BECAUSE YOU KNOW ME.
Treat me well even when you don't
KNOW ME.
SO, I SEE.
WHERE WERE YOU SO that we could help
you?
So, it means their goodness only comes
out to the people they know.
And then, the Bible ends by saying,
"Then he will answer them saying,
'Assuredly, I say to you, in as much as
you did not do it to one of the least of
this, you did not do it to me.'"
And this will go away
into everlasting punishment,
but the righteous into eternal what?
Eternal life.
We are discussing a well-grounded hope,
the hope of His second coming.
Ushering a new kingdom.
You might miss it, not because you are a
robber, a prostitute, a sexually moral
person. You might just miss it simply
because there was someone naked, but you
didn't dress them.
While you are at ease in your luxurious
home,
I had not where to lay my head.
While you crowded your wardrobe with
rich apparel,
I was destitute.
Today, people don't have wardrobes.
Today, people have walk-in closet.
Huh?
And there's an outfit for every event.
FOR EVERY CULTURE.
You look good.
We have outfits for every occasion from
every culture.
And Christ is saying, "While you crowded
your wardrobe with rich apparel, I WAS
DESTITUTE. WHILE YOU PURSUED your
pleasures, I LANGUISHED IN PRISON. ALL
THE DAYS OF YOUR LIFE, I was near you in
the person of these afflicted ones, but
you did not seek me."
Many have planned holidays even for this
December coming. This chapter will be
empty around December here.
Cuz people have planned holidays, booked
expensive flights, booked expensive
hotels. One end that could be gear
muley.
To visit the scenes of Christ's life on
Earth, to walk where he trod, to look
upon the lake beside which he loved to
teach.
And the hills and valleys on which his
eyes so often rested. People will come
back and say, "We went to Jordan River.
I even stepped inside and baptized was
baptized again."
We saw his tomb.
>> And I'm told those are two tourist sites
today.
Those are two tourist sites today.
Someone told me I've not gone. Someone
told me that when they went they were
shown three tombs, all of them claiming
that is where Christ was laid. And you
you're busy on Facebook updating your
status. This is where the savior rested.
And probably he's on a wrong tomb.
We need not go to Nazareth. We don't
need to go to Capernaum. We don't need
to go to Bethany in order to walk in the
steps of Jesus. We can still find his
footprints besides the sick bed, IN THE
HOVELS OF POVERTY, IN THE CROWDED ALLEYS
OF THE GREAT CITY. CHRIST SITS BEGGING
for food in the streets OF NAIROBI EVERY
OTHER TIME.
AND in every place where there are human
hearts in need of consolation, Christ is
right there.
In doing as Jesus did when on earth, we
shall walk in his footsteps.
Yeah, you don't need to lie on the bed
where he laid when he was buried.
The baptism you had is enough. You don't
need to go to Jordan.
And sink your legs there.
Walking in the footsteps of Christ.
Cuz you're chasing a cloud.
You're building your page.
Let me tell you why many young disciples
never advance beyond
the mere alphabet of Christian
experience.
It is because
we have neglected
to do this work.
Why you feel
empty?
You do Bible study.
You pray. You fast.
But you still feel you have not
had that rich deep experience with
Christ.
It is because you have neglected this
work.
When you first walked into the faith of
Christ,
there's a light that glowed in your
heart.
And this light,
I'm telling you without cringing, THIS
LIGHT THAT FIRST glowed in your in your
heart when you first met Christ can only
be kept alive by helping those that are
in need.
Active service
for the master.
There are people that have asked me,
"Why is it some people are so blessed?
They have certain powers that others
don't have."
You know,
when when you accept Christ, it's like
you have lit a small flame, probably a
candle flame.
The devil can see it and can tell you
have changed lanes. You're now with
Christ. He can see it. But that flame is
not strong enough to stop him from
attacking you.
Why? If he could If he could plan a coup
in heaven
with his maker,
you think when you accept Christ, you
shut THE DEVIL OUT? NO.
WHEN YOU FIRST MEET CHRIST, you light a
flame in your heart. The devil can see
it and he can tell you have moved from
the world and you've changed lanes.
You're now in the ranks OF GOD, BUT THAT
DOES NOT STOP HIM
FROM ATTACKING YOU.
THE ONLY TIME HE WILL not come close is
when you learn TO BLOW THE FLAME INTO A
FULL
FIRE.
AND IT STANDS FROM VAN SAYING, "NO."
That's a no good sign.
And the only way to fuel it into a fire
is when you will remain in active
service for the need, the suffering, and
the poor.
There is no other way.
No other way.
And that is why when the Lord
defined that these are my people called
by my name,
we were meant to be missionaries.
Missionaries who have a trade in their
hands. Our first calling is mission
work.
We were meant to be to be missionaries
who are accountants, not accountants who
are missionaries.
Our schools were meant to prepare
missionaries to the world, missionaries
home, missionaries abroad with a trade
in their hands.
There's a school I met
the other day when I was in
Romania for a conference.
Trying to operate on our original model
of education.
And you know, original model of
education, half the day a child is
supposed to be in class, half the day
they're supposed to be doing either some
industrial training, some domestic
training, or some manual training.
They're either in the farm or in some
industry, in the school.
Part of the industry that school has is
what we call mission aviation.
I have a big dream.
I hope it actualizes
for a school like that.
Training missionaries.
Not beggars. Not missionaries who are
beggars. Missionaries who have money
because they have a trade in their
hands.
They use it to make money
and fund ministry.
Like Paul, a missionary,
but a tent maker.
Or you think when they say he made
tents, it's some small tents he was
making?
Today when you see how people bury their
loved ones
and raise a tent of 2 million,
seats not inside yet. That's another
cost.
So, you can imagine if Paul was living
in our day,
Paul would be running Paul would be a
billionaire.
And that is why he says,
"Do not walk according to the ways we
didn't teach.
If anyone does not work,
he should not do what? Eat. Since we
came here, we have not eaten your bread.
YOU HAVE BEEN EATING OUR BREAD." A
MISSIONARY WHO HAS GONE TO preach
with his bread.
Not afraid to say THE TRUTH.
BECAUSE WHEN THEY SAY THE TRUTH THEY
WILL be told who you speak up.
PAUL HAD MONEY
TO FUND HIS MINISTRY.
LIKE IN A MINISTRY OF A COOL BAG
that we are missionaries but begging
we lose credibility.
People even question the God we are
worshiping.
We are talking about missionaries like
Christ.
A missionary with a trade of carpentry
in his what?
In his hand.
I've said this light can only be kept
alive by helping those in need. Self
must be forgotten
in honest work to do others good.
In the great judgment day as I conclude
those who have not worked for Christ
who have drifted along thinking of
themselves
will be placed by the judge himself
of the whole earth with those who did
evil
and together they receive the same
condemnation.
I am asking a sincere question.
How many together with me?
How many together with me
are asking the Lord
and are saying
Lord, I have kept myself unspotted from
the world.
When the Lord is looking for
prostitutes, you're not there.
The Lord is looking for liars, you're
not there.
When he's looking for drunkards, you're
When he's looking for witch doctors, you
are not found there.
Sorcery is not your cup of tea.
When the Lord is looking for for
adulterers, you are not there. You have
kept yourself unspotted from the world.
BUT YOU'RE SAYING
THAT GOD,
I have neglected ministry to the poor.
I have neglected ministry to the needy.
I have neglected ministry
to the suffering.
Work in me.
Work through me.
So that when the roll is called up
yonder,
may I be found among the sheep on the
right.
How many together with me?
I know all hands are up.
I may not ask people to come here.
But among those that are lifting their
hands,
so that we don't assume that we are all
members of this body.
Is there someone who would want to give
their lives today
for Christ? Is their first time?
Forget about those of us that we have
already. We just want to work for the
Lord. Anyone who is walking into this
faith for the first time?
Lest we forget, do we have?
Do we have?
If there is none,
let us all rise.
But Lord,
I have kept myself unspotted from the
world,
but
for failing to work for you,
I may not see you.
As our choristers come to lead us
in song number 216
When the roll is called up yonder.
As you search your heart
before I do the final prayer.
Search your heart.
I will ask Natalie to come for the final
prayer.
Do a prayer yourself as we sing.
Whisper it to the Lord.
It's time I also visited someone in
prison, someone I don't know.
It's time I fed the poor, someone I
don't know.
Yes.
Song 216.
>> Let's sing.
>> When the trumpet of the Lord shall sound
and time shall be no more, and the
morning breaks eternal bright and fair.
When the savior shall gather all their
own on the
other shore,
and the
roll is called up yonder,
I'll be there.
>> When the roll
When the roll is called up yonder,
I'll be there.
When the roll
When the
roll is called up yonder,
I'll be there.
When the roll
When the roll is called
up yonder, I'll be there.
When the roll is called up yonder,
I'll be there.
On that bright and cloudless morning
when the dead in
>> Let us labor.
Let us humble ourselves.
The Lord is here.
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against
us.
Lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is thy kingdom, thy power, and
thy glory
forever and ever.
Amen.
He who is seated
on the throne
above,
no one
can bring you down.
Sometimes
I might ask, "Who created God?"
No one created you.
You are there
in past times,
past history
that we are yet to know.
And when the roll is called up yonder,
this is one of the things I would want
to ask.
Let me be
a fool in righteousness at this moment.
Thank you for this Sabbath.
It is very rare
to find the house of God full of His
Spirit.
How do we know
you are here?
Well, I just saw your children raise
their hands.
I just saw your children outwardly
confirming the work in their hearts.
Thank you
for tabernacling with us today.
Indeed,
the most
dangerous combination here
on earth
and in the history of the universe
is the human and the divine.
May your name be glorified.
We serve a God who has not told us
to do wickedly with our beloved
that he should give us power.
You have not told us
to make our hands filthy.
to shed blood of the innocent
in the name of seeking riches,
in the name of power.
This I realize you are a loving God.
You give freely.
You give out of love. You are no
respecter of persons.
In the underworld,
the master
of demons,
the master of wickedness,
indeed he is a tough master.
I learn
anyone who would not attain,
anyone would not do as he wills,
then that would be the end of them.
But here we are
singing with our hearts out.
Your children even holding a musical
instrument
expressing
their love to you.
There's no hard thing here.
Yes, there's the hard work,
the straight and narrow way, which is
the width of one man, the width of Jesus
Christ.
May your name be glorified.
Indeed, a man went out to sow,
and some seeds fell
on thorns.
Some seeds fell on stony ground.
Some seeds, I am glad, fell on fertile
soil.
And they produced fruits, some 30-fold,
some 60-fold.
The enemy of souls is at work.
I refuse him in the name of Jesus
Christ. You have no place in this in
this meeting, in this gathering, in the
name of Jesus Christ. At this name, you
shall bow in the name of Jesus Christ.
Yes, you stand before the Lord as you
accuse us of our sins.
This I boast.
This I am
claiming humbly before my loving savior,
my sins have been forgiven.
I have been pardoned.
Thank you for the power
in our hands.
We don't know who we are.
We don't have your vision.
You have called us into primitive faith.
Help us to cast aside all pride
and all questions,
all questioning.
If you say today,
you want to send anyone,
where are you?
We shall say, "Here we are, Lord.
Send us."
Thank you
for the advent message.
Indeed, we leave
with our hearts full of hope.
There is a big difference.
And this is recognized. May it be seen
in our places of work.
May it be seen in our homes.
The hope
that fills the pilgrim's heart
is the coming of the Lord.
May your name be exalted.
May you be lifted high.
This is my plea in the name of Jesus
Christ. Amen. May the grace of our Lord
Jesus Christ, the love of God the
Father, the fellowship of the Holy
Spirit be with us now and forevermore.
Thank you.